Guide to the Carling I. Malouf Papers 1891-2006
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Carling I. Malouf papers
1891-2006
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 640
Malouf, Carling I., 1916-2007
43.75 linear feet
This collection contains correspondence, notes, photographs, audio material, and visual material related to Anthropology Professor Carling Malouf’s work and activities at the University of Montana in Missoula, as well as his research on Native American tribes of the Northwest and the Plains.
Biographical Note
Carling I. Malouf was born in Fillmore, Utah, in 1916. In 1940, he graduated with a bachelor’s degree in business and economics from the University of Utah. As an undergraduate, Malouf worked on an archaeological dig in central Utah, which compelled him to obtain a master’s degree in anthropology at the University of Utah. While working on his master’s, Malouf met his wife Arline, and the couple was married in 1941.
Wartime military service during WWII interrupted Malouf’s work on a doctorate in anthropology at Columbia University. During his service, the couple moved to various posts and stations in Utah, California, and Arizona. In 1946, Malouf was able to resume his doctoral studies at Columbia and he graduated 2 years later. Shortly after graduation in 1948, Malouf was offered a faculty position at The University of Montana in Missoula and he, Arline, and their four young children returned to the west.
While at the University of Montana, Carling Malouf played large role in the birth and development of the departments of Anthropology and Native American Studies, and was chair of the department of Anthropology from 1969-1977. Malouf was an avid researcher in the fields of Archaeology, Ethnology, and Native American Studies. His primary research interests included Native American tribes of Montana, the Plains, and the greater Northwest, comparative ethnology, and archaeological sites in Montana, including Fort Owen. Malouf’s involvement in anthropology and archaeology also extended outside of the University system. He was a supporter and a member of the board of directors of the Montana Archaeological Society, an organization devoted to promoting research and public involvement in archaeology in the state of Montana. Malouf contributed many articles to the Society’s publication, Archaeology in Montana, from the years 1959-2000.
Malouf was also involved in the development of the Head Start program. In 1960, he was a member of the Montana Child Welfare Committee, a group that made periodic reports to the White House regarding the state of education and youth in Montana. He became a consultant in Anthropology for Project Head Start for the Office of Economic Opportunity. In 1969, Malouf, along with 150 other education specialists, was invited to the White House to a conference for the development of the Head Start Program. Later, he and his wife toured reservations in Montana, Idaho, and Wyoming to provide information and ideas to administrators for the new programs.
Malouf retired from the University of Montana in 1988 and was honored that same year at the Montana Archaeological Society’s Annual Conference. Following his retirement, Malouf continued to do research and publish articles. Carling Malouf died in March of 2007 at the age of 90.
The collection contains clippings, correspondence, notes, photographs, publications, slides, audio material, and visual material related to Carling Malouf’s work and activities in the University of Montana’s Anthropology Department, as well as Malouf’s research on Native American tribes of the Northwest and the Plains. Materials include papers related to the history of the University of Montana’s Department of Anthropology; the history of Kyi-Yo (spelled Kyiyo since 2015), the University of Montana’s Native American Student Association; and the Native American Studies Department at the University of Montana. The collection also contains materials related to the AIM/Wounded Knee incident and ensuing trial, research on Native American Education, materials related to Montana archaeology digs and sites, and photographs and notes related to the tribes of Montana. Also included are papers, correspondence, and notes related to Carling Malouf’s involvement in the development of the Head Start program, as well as correspondence, notes, newsletters, and publications related to the Montana Archaeological Society.
This collection has been divided into five series: Series I: University Materials (1954-2004), contains notes, departmental budget information, intradepartmental correspondence, clippings, and publications related to Carling Malouf’s role in the Department of Anthropology and the Department of Native American Studies at the University of Montana. Series II: Subject Files (1891-2006), contains materials related to Carling Maoulf’s research and interests in archaeology, anthropology, and the Native American tribes of Montana. The series contains notes, correspondence, clippings, and publications. The series also contains photographs and negatives, most of which were not taken by Malouf, but were collections he considered relevant to his research. Series III: Audio Materials, (ca. 1950-2005 and n.d.), contains reel-to-reel audio and audiocassettes, A portion of this series is recorded talks and lectures of Carling Malouf, and recordings of the songs and stories of Native American tribes of the Northwest. Another portion consists of copies of prerecorded materials related to the Native Americans in the southwest. Series IV: Slides, (1939-1975 and n.d.), consists of slides and a slide index. Some of these images were taken by Carling Malouf and are arranged by tribe name or by the name of a site of archaeological interest. Others are likely commercial slides used in the classroom. In 2012 all slides were removed from carousels and boxes and placed in sleeves. Series V: Moving Image Material, was added in 2012 because of a large addition of 8mm films to the collection. The series also includes DVDs and VHS cassettes.
The collection is divided into five series:
Series I: University Materials, 1954-2004, 4.0 linear feet
Series II: Subject Files, 1891-2006, 30.75 linear feet
Series III: Audio Materials, circa 1950-2005, 1.5 linear feet
Series IV: Slides, 1939-1975, 5.0 linear feet
Series V: Moving Image Material, circa 1950-1970, 2.5 linear feet
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula. Materials from a binder of correspondence are restricted for privacy reasons until 2017. Folder 1 of box 65 is restricted for privacy reasons. Half of the audio is restricted until further review. One film is restricted because it contains information about Native American burial sites.
The majority of these materials were in the possession of Carling Malouf until his death and then were transferred directly to the Archives in the summer of 2007. A portion of the materials were donated by Malouf to the Archives between 2003 and 2006. Two binders of correspondence were loaned by Malouf to the UM Foundation and were transferred to the Archives following his death. Two binders were held by UM Professor of Anthropology G.G. Weix. One was donated in 2009 and one in 2010. An additional set of 8mm films was donated by Weix in 2012. In 2011, an additional 25 linear feet of materials were donated by Malouf's daugher, Sydney Hulla.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Head Start Program (U.S.); Kyi-Yo Native American Student Association (University of Montana--Missoula); Kyiyo Native American Student Association (University of Montana--Missoula); University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.). Dept. of Anthropology.; University of Montana--Missoula--Faculty; University of Montana--Missoula--Students--Societies, etc.
Demersville (Mont.)--Photographs; Fort Owen (Mont.)
Anthropology--Study and teaching (Higher)--Montana--Missoula; Indian college students--Montana--Missoula--Societies, etc.; Indians of North America--Study and teaching.; Indians of North America--Montana; Kalispel Indians; Kootenai Indians; Salish Indians; Siksika Indians
Sound Recordings; Moving Images; Photographs
Archaeology; Native Americans; Colleges and Universities
Anthropologists--Montana--Missoula.; Anthropology teachers--Montana--Missoula.
- University Materials, 1954-2004; Series I; 4.0 linear feet
  Notes, departmental budget information, intradepartmental correspondence, clippings, and publications related to Carling Malouf’s role in the Department of Anthropology and the Department of Native American Studies at the University of Montana.
  - Anthropological Education, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 66/1)
  - Anthropology Department Budget, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Anthropology Department Correspondence, 1948-1991 (Box-folder 66/2-3)
  - Anthropology Department Correspondence, 1957-2004 (Box-folder 1/2-5)
  - Anthropology Department Graduate Students, 1956-1984 (Box-folder 1/6-8)
  - Anthropology Department History, volume I, circa 1960-circa 1971 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Anthropology Department History volume II, circa 1987-1998 (Box-folder 2/2-3)
  - Anthropology Department History, volume III, circa 1957-2003 (Box-folder 2/4-6)
  - Anthropology Department History, volume IV, circa 1963-1996 (Box-folder 3/1-3)
  - Anthropology Department Social Studies Papers, 1981 (Box-folder 66/4)
  - Anthropology Department Syllabi, undated (Box-folder 66/5)
  - Ludvig G. Browman Fellowship in Museum Studies, 1987-1987 (Box-folder 66/6)
  - Kyi-Yo and Native American Studies Department, volume I, 1954-1969 (Box-folder 3/4-6)
  - Kyi-Yo and Native American Studies Department, volume II, 1970-2000 (Box-folder 3/7-8)
  - Kyi-Yo and Native American Studies Department, volume II, 1970-2000 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Kyi-Yo and Native American Studies Department, volume III, circa 1971-1997 (Box-folder 4/2-4)
  - Kyi-Yo Conference, Student Responses, 1973 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Malouf Faculty Evaluation, 1962-1981 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Malouf Faculty Evaluation, 1974-1989 (Box-folder 66/7)
  - Montana Committee for the Humanities, Indian Conference Series, 1972 (Box-folder 66/8)
  - "Family and Kinship: Designed for Instruction of Indian Children in the Third Grade" by Georganne Richter, 1969 (Box-folder 66/9)
  - Native American Studies Program Newsletter, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 66/10-11)
  - NDEA Institute in English for Speakers of Other Languages, 1967 (Box-folder 66/12)
  - Student Papers, RESTRICTED, 1968-1989 (Box-folder 78/1-4)
  - Title Pages for Some Covers for Anthropology and Sociology Papers, 1954 and undated (Box-folder 76/13)
  - The University of Montana History, circa 1954-2002 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - The University of Montana History, circa 1954-2002 (Box-folder 5/1-2)
  - The University of Montana Research Grant Application, 1975 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - The University of Montana Training Institutes, 1957-1975 (Box-folder 5/4-8)
  - Various subjects related to Anthropology Department, Biology and people, circa 1954-2002 (Box-folder 64/1-4)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth, Correspondence, 1959 (Box-folder 66/13)
- Subject Files, 1891-2006; Series II; 30.75 linear feet
  Materials related to Carling Malouf’s research and interests in archaeology, anthropology, and the Native American Tribes of Montana. The series contains notes, correspondence, clippings, and publications. The series also contains photographs and negatives, most of which were not taken by Malouf but were collections he considered relevant to his research. The series has been arranged alphabetically by folder title. The content in the folder titled 'Helping Indians' has been restricted for privacy reasons.
  - A View of Montana, undated (Box-folder 66/14)
  - Afro-Americans in Montana, circa 1988-1997 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Akwesasne Notes, 1974 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Alan P. Merriam, Publications and Letters, circa 1949-1965 (Box-folder 6/3-6)
  - Amateur Archaeologists, 1954-1981; Correspondence (Box-folder 6/7-9)
  - American Anthropological Society, Western States Branch, 1942-1961; Correspondence and Society Newsletter (Box-folder 6/10)
  - American Indian Development, Incorporated, D’Arcy McNickle, 1966-1967; Report on Indian Affairs workshop and correspondence (Box-folder 7/1)
  - American Scholar, Questionnaire, undated (Box-folder 66/15)
  - Ann Kootenay Biographies, undated (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Annual Convention of the National Congress of American Indians, Address by Commissioner of Indian Affairs, Glenn L. Emmons, 1955 (Box-folder 66/16)
  - Annual Meeting of the Indian Rights Association, Address by Commissioner of Indian Affairs, Glenn L. Emmons, 1954 (Box-folder 66/17)
  - Anthropologists, Biographies and Clippings, 1951-1988 (Box-folder 7/3-5)
  - Anthropologists, Letters and Papers, volume I, 1939-1988 (Box-folder 7/6-9)
  - Anthropologists, Letters and Papers, volume II, 1949-2003 (Box-folder 8/1-4)
  - Anthropologists, Letters and Papers, volume III, 1951-1995 (Box-folder 8/5-7)
  - Archaeology Correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Archaeology Correspondence, 1964-1987 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Archaeology, Antelope Creek Mine, Converse County, Wyoming, 1982 (Box-folder 8/10-11)
  - Archaeology, North America, 1958 and undated (Box-folder 66/18)
  - Archaeology, Western Montana, 1951-1969 (Box-folder 9/1-4)
  - Article Index, 3x5 Cards, undated (Box-folder 67)
  - Article Index, 3x5 Cards, undated (Box-folder 68)
  - Artifacts from Flathead Lake, undated (Box-folder 69/1)
  - Assiniboine, 1964-2003; Correspondence, academic and student papers, clippings, and photographs of artifacts (Box-folder 9/5-6)
  - Assiniboine, Chippewa, Cree, Crow, Cheyenne, Sioux, Blackfeet, circa 1906-2004; Photographs, publications, clippings, and newsletters (Box-folder 10/1-3)
  - Athletic Games, North American Indian, undated (Box-folder 69/2)
  - Barrier Canyon, Utah, undated (Box-folder 69/3)
  - Bibliographies, 1953-1980 (Box-folder 69/4-5)
  - Ellen Bigsam, undated (Box-folder 69/8)
  - Bigsams, Photos and Clippings, 1923-1999 (Box-folder 10/4-6)
  - Bitterroot Valley, Archaeological Sites, 1952 (Box-folder 69/6)
  - Blackfoot River Water Recreation Study, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Bob Scriver, Artist, 1968-2003; Publications, correspondence, and notes (Box-folder 10/8-9)
  - Book List, 1984 (Box-folder 69/7)
  - Brigham Young University Anthropology, 1954-1988 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Buffalo Jump, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 11/2-4)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs Information, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 11/5-8)
  - Burials, 1951-1970; Correspondence, clippings, notes, and photographs (Box-folder 12/1-2)
  - Camas News, circa 1967 (Box-folder 69/9)
  - Cantonment Jordan, undated (Box-folder 69/10)
  - Cantonment Stevens, undated (Box-folder 69/11)
  - Canyon Ferry, 1949-1968 (Box-folder 69/12-14)
  - "Ceremonial Life of Montana Indians and Neighboring Tribes," by Ethel M. Garbe, undated (Box-folder 69/16)
  - Char-Koosta, circa 1918-1972 and n.d (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Cherokee, 1999; Clippings (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Chief Plenty Coups, undated (Box-folder 69/15)
  - Chief Walker, Article, undated (Box-folder 70/1)
  - Cognitions on Polarity Thinking, undated (Box-folder 70/2)
  - Considerations in the Counseling of Indians, undated (Box-folder 70/3)
  - Corps of Discovery Statue, undated (Box-folder 70/4)
  - Cree-Chippewa, circa 1905; Photographs (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Crow Biographies, 1935-1996 (Box-folder 12/6-7)
  - Crow, Pentecostalism among, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 12/8-10)
  - Crow, 1954-2001; Published sources, photographs, and notes (Box-folder 13/1-4)
  - Cultural Resource Management, undated (Box-folder 70/5)
  - Dakota or Sioux, 1954-1999; Clippings, articles, and student papers (Box-folder 13/5-8)
  - Demersville, 1889-1969; Clippings and articles (Box-folder 14/1-2)
  - Deward Walker, 1967-1993; Publications, correspondence, and notes (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Dorothy Johnson, 1952-2005; Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Dusenberry, 1954-1966; Correspondence and journals (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Federal Trusteeship Over Indian Lands, 1960-1967 and undated (Box-folder 70/6)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Activities, 1891-circa 1950; Photographs (Box-folder 14/6-7)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Activities, circa 1965-1996; Photographs, clippings, and notes (Box-folder 15/1-4)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Biographies Notes, A-H, volume III, 1957-1997; Ninepipes and Bigsams (Box-folder 15/5-8)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Biographies Notes, I-Z, volume III, 1926-1996; Ninepipes and Bigsams (Box-folder 16/1-4)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Notes, 1901-1996 (Box-folder 16/5-8)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Notes, volume I, 1949-2004 (Box-folder 17/1-4)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Notes, volume II, 1912-1997 (Box-folder 17/5-8)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Notes, volume III, 1977-2001 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Persons, volume I, circa 1905-1966; Ninepipes and Bigsams (Box-folder 18/2-5)
  - Flathead and Pend d’Orielle Persons, volume II, circa 1905-1990; Ninepipes and Bigsams (Box-folder 18/6-8)
  - Flathead Culture Book Manuscript, undated (Box-folder 19/1-3)
  - Flathead Indian Families, 1952-2005; Ninepipes and Bigsams (Box-folder 19/4-5)
  - Flathead, Kutenai, and Upper Pend D'Orielle Genealogies, 1952 and undated (Box-folder 70/7)
  - Fort Belknap Reservation: Assiniboine and Gros Ventre, 1937-1987 and n.d.; Copy of the charter of the Fort Belknap reservation, publications, clippings, and student papers (Box-folder 19/6-8)
  - Fort Owen Book Manuscript, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 20/1-4)
  - Fort Owen Excavations and Research, volume I, 1954-1988 (Box-folder 20/5-6)
  - Fort Owen Excavations and Research, volume II, 1954-1988 (Box-folder 21/1-4)
  - Fort Owen Site Plat Map, undated (Box-folder OS 77/1)
  - Forts, circa 1950-2002; Clippings and notes (Box-folder 21/5-7)
  - George W. Arthur Thesis: An introduction to the Ecology of Early Historic Communal Bison Hunting Among the Northern Plains Indians, 1974 (Box-folder 21/8-9)
  - Gosiute, undated (Box-folder 70/8)
  - Great Basin, undated (Box-folder 70/9)
  - Head Start in Education, 1965; Photographs and notes (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Head Start Program Involvement, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 22/2-5)
  - Helena Area, Canyon Ferry, circa 1950-1990 (Box-folder 22/6-8)
  - Helping Indians - RESTRICTED, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 65/1)
  - Historic Archaeology and Preservation, 1966-2003 (Box-folder 23/1-3)
  - Historical Archaeology, 1958-2004 (Box-folder 70/10)
  - Historical Archaeology Library, 1975 (Box-folder 23/4-6)
  - Indian Affairs, 1945-1960 (Box-folder 24/1-2)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts, undated (Box-folder 24/3-5)
  - Indian Caves, Clipping, 1964 (Box-folder 70/11)
  - Indian Court and Native Americans, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Indian Economics, circa 1958-2000; Conference proceedings, publications, and clippings (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Indian Education, volume I, 1958-1998 (Box-folder 25/1-4)
  - Indian Education, 2006 (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Indian Education, Training Teachers, 1958-1975 (Box-folder 26/1-5)
  - Indian Health, Medicine, Native to Modern, circa 1952-2000 (Box-folder 26/6-7)
  - Indian Newspaper Clippings, volume I, circa 1965-1971; Wassaja Tribal Spokesman, ABC (Box-folder 27/1-3)
  - Indian Newspaper Clippings, various subjects, volume II, circa 1965-1971; Wassaja Tribal Spokesman, ABC (Box-folder 27/4-6)
  - Indian Record Newsletters, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Indian Specialists Employment Services Training, circa 1965-1967 (Box-folder 28/1-3)
  - Indian Voices Publications, circa 1962-1982 (Box-folder 28/4-7)
  - Indian/White Relationships, circa 1959-1996; Clippings, articles, and student papers (Box-folder 28/8)
  - Indians of Montana, 1904-1977; Notes, student papers, clippings, and articles (Box-folder 28/9)
  - Indians of Montana, 1904-1977; Notes, student papers, clippings, and articles (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Israel, Archaeology, circa 1970 (Box-folder 70/12-13)
  - John C. Ewers, circa 1981-2002; Correspondence and publications (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Kalispel Indians, 1991 (Box-folder 70/14)
  - Klamath Indians, 1958-1978 and undated (Box-folder 70/15)
  - Kootenai, 1953-2005; Clippings, geneology trees, and notes (Box-folder 29/3-4)
  - Kootenai and Salish Notes, 1950-1966 (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Kutenai (Kootenai) Extras, 1959-1969; Notes, correspondence, and publications (Box-folder 29/6-8)
  - Kutenai (Kootenai) Notes, volume I, 1954-1976 (Box-folder 30/1-3)
  - Kutenai (Kootenai) Notes, volume II, 1952-1997 (Box-folder 30/4)
  - Kutenai (Kootenai) Photos-Persons, volume I, circa 1906-1984 (Box-folder 30/5-7)
  - Kutenai (Kootenai) Photos-Persons, volume II, circa 1906-1950 (Box-folder 31/1-3)
  - "Kutenai Pipes," by Thain White, undated (Box-folder 70/16)
  - Kutenai Photographs, 1949-circa 1995 and undated (Box-folder 70/17)
  - Language Analysis, 1931-1980; Articles and student papers (Box-folder 31/4-5)
  - Leslie Davis, 1963-1999; Thesis and correspondence (Box-folder 31/6-8)
  - Madison Buffalo Jump, 1956-1963 and undated (Box-folder 71/1)
  - Malouf Family History, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 71/2)
  - Marcia Cross Thesis: Bighorn Sheep and the Salish World View, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 31/9)
  - Methodology, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 71/3)
  - Michio Kitahara, 1972-1988; Articles and correspondence (Box-folder 32/1)
  - Miscellaneous Archaeological Site Sketches, Unlabled, undated (Box-folder 71/4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1996 and undated (Box-folder 71/5)
  - Miscellaneous Photograph Captions, undated (Box-folder 71/6)
  - Miscellaneous Writing Fragments, undated (Box-folder 71/7)
  - Missionaries: Effects on Native Americans, circa 1977-1991 (Box-folder 32/2-3)
  - Missouri River Headwaters Archaeology, 1960 (Box-folder 71/8)
  - Missouri River In North Dakota, Archaeological Site, undated (Box-folder 71/9)
  - Montana and Wyoming Archaeology Sites, Yellowstone National Park, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 32/4-5)
  - Montana and Wyoming, Original Field Notes in Archeaology, 1940-1969 (Box-folder 71/10-12)
  - Montana Archaeological Society, 1959-1995; Meeting minutes, correspondence, meeting programs and agendas (Box-folder 32/6-7)
  - Montana Archaeology, Buffalo Jumps, 1962 (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Montana Archaeology, Canyon Ferry, near Helena, Montana, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Montana Archaeology, Flathead Indian Reservation, 1958-1993 (Box-folder 33/3-6)
  - Montana Archaeology, Flathead Lake, 1953-1995 (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Montana Archaeology, Glacier National Park, 1963 (Box-folder 34/1-3)
  - Montana Archaeology, Missoula Valley, Lake Missoula, 1952-2000 (Box-folder 34/4-6)
  - Montana Archaeology, Northwest Montana, 1956-1983 (Box-folder 35/1-5)
  - Montana Archaeology, Southeast and North Central Montana, 1950-1989 (Box-folder 35/6-9)
  - Montana Archaeology, Thain White Notes and Photos, circa 1890-1955 (Box-folder 36/1-4)
  - Montana Archaeology, volume I, 1941-1995; Publications, clippings, student field notes, photographs with captions, correspondence, notes and maps (Box-folder 36/5-8)
  - Montana Archaeology, volume II, 1941-1963; Publications, clippings, student field notes, photographs with captions, correspondence, notes and maps (Box-folder 37/1)
  - Montana Archaeology, volume III, 1950-1966; Publications, clippings, student field notes, photographs with captions, correspondence, notes and maps (Box-folder 37/2-3)